<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Go on Aliff - Blog</title>
    <link>https://aliff-blog.vercel.app/tags/go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Go on Aliff - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Aliff</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 08:15:55 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aliff-blog.vercel.app/tags/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building RESTful APIs with Go</title>
      <link>https://aliff-blog.vercel.app/posts/building_restful_apis_with_go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 08:15:55 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aliff-blog.vercel.app/posts/building_restful_apis_with_go/</guid>
      <description>Building RESTful APIs with Go Understanding RESTful APIs REST (Representational State Transfer) is an architectural style that defines a set of constraints for creating web services. RESTful APIs are web services that adhere to these constraints, allowing for efficient communication over the internet by using standard HTTP methods like GET, POST, PUT, and DELETE.&#xA;Why Go for API Development? Go, also known as Golang, is a statically typed, compiled programming language designed at Google.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generics in Go</title>
      <link>https://aliff-blog.vercel.app/posts/generics_in_go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 08:07:05 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aliff-blog.vercel.app/posts/generics_in_go/</guid>
      <description>Generics in Go: A Comprehensive Guide Understanding Generics Generics allow programmers to write flexible, reusable functions and types that can work with any data type. Before generics, Go developers had to rely on interfaces and type assertions to achieve similar functionality, which could be less efficient and more error-prone.&#xA;Why Generics? Generics can significantly improve your Go code by:&#xA;Reducing Code Duplication: Write a function or data structure once, and use it with different types.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Multithreaded App in Go</title>
      <link>https://aliff-blog.vercel.app/posts/creating_a_multithreaded_app_in_go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 07:48:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aliff-blog.vercel.app/posts/creating_a_multithreaded_app_in_go/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Multithreaded App in Go: A Comprehensive Guide Multithreading is a pivotal concept that allows applications to perform multiple operations simultaneously, making them more efficient and responsive. Go, with its lightweight goroutines, provides a powerful and straightforward way to implement concurrency. This blog post aims to guide you through the process of creating a multithreaded application in Go, highlighting best practices and common pitfalls to avoid.&#xA;Introduction to Goroutines At the heart of Go&amp;rsquo;s concurrency model are goroutines, which are functions or methods that run concurrently with other functions or methods.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
